Charles Bukowski papers, 1944-1977
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Charles Bukowski, 1944-1977
MS 148
Bukowski, Charles
Contains published and unpuplished books, periodicals, manuscripts, letters, audio recordings, and artwork from 1964-1974, of the poet, novelist, and screenwriter, Charles Bukowski. (
6.3 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Charles Bukowski was born in Andernach, Germany August 16, 1920. He emigrated with his family to the United States when he was three and grew up poor in Los Angeles. Poet, novelist, screenwriter, and denizen of the mean streets of LA, he wrote from experience. Bukowski is generally considered a "beat poet" though he never associated with beat writers. His language, subject matter and world view reflect a life and love of drink, women and horses. Bukowski was a prolific, some say a compulsive writer. He rose from being a local literary cult figure to wide acclaim following the success of his screenplay for the motion picture Barfly. The screen play is based on his semi-autobiographical novel Factotum in which a down and out poet (Mickey Rourke) meets a barfly (Faye Dunaway). The character enjoys fleeting flame before sinking into drink and oblivion. Unlike, his character, Charles Bukowski realized financial success before his death in San Pedro, California on March 9, 1994. Sales of his work are reported at over a million volumes a year.
Organization
This collection is organized into five series:
I. Nola Express, 1967-1973
II. Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material, 1963-1975
III. Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski, 1960-1977
IV. Other Publications, 1944-1976
V. Audio and Visual Materials, 1960-1980
Scope and Content Note
Consists mainly of Bukowski's books and chapbooks, as well as periodical publications that contain his writings. The finding aid indexes 71 other contemporary writers represented in these periodicals, including Diane Wakoski and Fielding Dawson. Jim Roman, book-seller, is the primary correspondent, 1964-1974, both with Bukowski, and with other people about him. Some letters contain material relating to colleagues Jon Edgar Webb and his Loujon Press, and also John Martin of the Black Sparrow Press. Additional correspondence, as well as poetry, stories, and drawings are from Bukowski to Darlene Fife and Robert Head, of the New Orleans underground newspaper, Nola Express, from 1967-1973. Also contains unpublished poetry and prose manuscripts; drawings and cartoons; reviews; photographs; and audio cassettes of Bukowski reading his works. Drawings include self-portraits, and are done in acrylics, watercolor, ink, and pencil. Ephemera consists of poetry postcards, broadsides, flyers, and posters; some are signed by Bukowski. This collection is continued by MS 171.
Bukowski, Charles--archives.; Webb, Jon Edgar.; Martin, John.; Roman, Jim--Correspondence.; Wakoski, Diane.; Dawson, Fielding.; Black Sparrow Press.; Loujon Press.; Poets, American--20th century--Sources.; Authors, American|--20th century--Sources.; Small press books--Specimens; Underground press publications--Specimens.; Correspondence; Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Nola Express, 1967-1973
  Poetry, short stories, letters, drawings all to the New Orleans underground magazine Nola Express (addressed to Darlene Fife and Robert Head) from October 1967 to July 1973. All of the poems and stories were published in Nola Express. Some of the poems and stories were published in other magazines and books sometimes in a slightly different form. Some of the correspondence is undated, some of it has become separated from the manucripts for which it was the cover.
  - Nola Express: Poems, Stories, Letters, Drawings. 1967, 1969, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes: Poem: The Status Q. for Me and Yew. Story: The Fuck Machine. Story: The Cat in the Closet. Story: Rape! Rape! Story: The Beginner.
  - Nola Express: Poems, Stories, Letters, Drawings. June-December 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes:
    Poem: "I Think of the Little Men."
    Story: "Love It or Leave It."
    Story: "All the Pussy We Want."
  - Nola Express: Stories and Letters-"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Nola Express: Stories, Letters, Drawings-"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." January 1972-April 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Nola Express: Stories, Letters, Drawings-"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." May-June 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Nola Express: Stories, Letters, Drawings-"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." July-September 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Nola Express: Stories, Letters, Drawings-"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." October-December 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nola Express: Poems and Stories. Circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    "Notes of a Dirty Old Man"
    "a sound in the brush"
    "good night, sweet jello leaves"
    "my landlady and my landlord:
    "left with the dog"
    "ATD for You and Me"
    "The Sex Fiends"
  - Nola Express: Stories, Letters, Drawings'"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." January-February 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Nola Express: Stories, Letters, Drawings'"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." March 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Nola Express: Stories, Letters, Drawings'"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." April-May 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Nola Express: Stories, Letters, Drawings'"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." June-July 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Nola Express: Undated Correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nola Express: Undated Poems. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    'life"
    'horse from hell"
    "piss"
    "the loner"
    "nazi"
    "The Beautiful Lady"
    "Art Class"
    "New Mexico"
    "A $15 boy and a $15,000 casket"
  - Nola Express: Undated Stories, Part One. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    "A Lively Love Affair"
    "Would You suggest Writing as a Career?"
    "The Silver Christ of Santa Fe"
    "Life is a Texas Whorehouse"
    "Purple as an Iris"
  - Nola Express: Undated Stories, Part Two. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    "The White Beard"
    "Notes of a Potential Suicide"
    "Scenes from the Big Time"
    "Swaztika"
    "6 inches"
    "The Fountains of Home"
  - Nola Express: Undated Stories, Letters, Part One. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    "notes upon the tigress"
    "livin' in a great big way"
    "warn asses"
    "what's the use of a title?"
    "another poem about a drunk and then I'll let you go""
  - Nola Express: Undated Storeis, Letters, Part Two-"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nola Express: Undated Stories, Letters, Drawings, Part Three. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    "Upon the Landslide Victory of Richard Nixon"
    "the creation of the morning line"
    "the chicken"
    "The Adding Machine"
    "Charles"
    "the violin player"
    "tv"
  - Nola Express: Undated Stories, Part Four-"Notes of a Dirty Old Man." (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nola Express: Casette of Readings by Bukowski for Nola Express. See Also Box 18, folder 8. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Correspondence with Jim Roman, May 5, 1964-December 17, 1974
    Holographs
    Orginal typeprints, wome wih orginal drawings
    Water colors, some with decorated envelopes
  - Nola Express: Stories, Letters, Drawings. 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nola Express: Stories, Letters, Drawings. 1967, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series II: Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material, 1963-1975
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material: Correspondence with John Martin, Publisher of Black Sparrow Press. Includes six sketches apparently intended for but not used in Factotum (Box 10). (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material. 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Letter to Jon and Lou Webb, publishers of Loujon Press, signed facsimile of original letter, November 23, 1963
    Letter to Willan and Ruthie, Octover 30, 1970
    Letter to Norman Moser, December 15, 1970
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material: Correspondence Concerning Bukowksi and His Work, Part One. 1963-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Letter from Jon Webb to Jim Roman, March 4 and 5, 1963
    Letter from Ben Tibbs to Jim Roman concering cover drawing for Flower, Fist, and Bestial Wail (Vol. 4 is the original framed drawing)
    Letter from Taylor Hackford to Jim Roman concerning half-hour television film Bukowski, 1973
    Reviews of film and related material (poster for this film is in Vol. 17, folder 13).
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material: Correspondence Concerning Bukowski and His Work, Part Two. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Taylor Hackford to/from Jim Roman, September 23 and 29, 1975 concerning Post Office as a movie
    Proposal for the film signed by Charles Bukowski
    Budget outline (Box 6, folder 6 contains the screenplay)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material: Unpublished Poems (Manuscripts are Signed). (Box 2, Folder 12)
    "For a Lady Who Expected Rupert Brooke"
    "watermelon"
    "Song of My Typewriter"
    "artistic selfishness, yes I have it---"
    "visit to Venice"
    "The Island"
    "4 on 6"
    "the dead came running sideways..."
    "2 carnations," April 26, 1971
    "Bukowski"
    "I found this atomic stockpile"
    "the big bulls in the pisspot"
    "a poorly night"
    "the big new year's party"
    "Goodwill"
    "American Flag Shirts," April 4, 1971
    "injustice is just another name for original beauty"
    "lost"
    "this is the way it works"
    "pain," April 25, 1971
    "the justice of the blood"
    "lord"
    "Man in Bed"
    "Radio"
    "the majesty of our imperfection"
    "?,"
    "Have You Ever Kissed a Panther?"
    "that big nice girl who came in to change the sheets"
    "the killers"
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material:: Unpublished Short Stories (Manuscripts are Signed). (Box 2, Folder 13)
    "The House of Horrors"
    Two "Notes of a Dirty Old Man"
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material: Book Reviews, Mostly Photocopies. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Includes reviews of:
    Factotum
    Mockingbird Wish Me Luck
    Burning in Water, Drowning in Flame
    Love is a Dog from Hell
    Life and Death in the Charity Ward
    Post Office
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material: Photographs. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Two small photos, both signed, circa 1963
    One signed photos, circa 1964
    Five signed photos by Richard Robinson, 1975
    Two signed photos (duplicates) by Hogan
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Material: Flyers. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Loujon Press flyer for It Catches My Heart in Its Hands (signed)
    Black Sparrow Press flyers for The Days Run Away,,, and Factotum (two copies)
    City Lights Books flyer for various titles
    Earth Books flyer for record Bukowski, 90 Minutes in Hell
    Underwater Poetry Festival flyer/posters in which Charles Bukowski is one of the featured participants
- Series III: Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski, 1960-1977
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Flower, Fist and Bestial Wail, Eureka, California, Hearse Press (Hearse Chapbook 5). Also includes presentation copy to Jim Roman. Original framed cover drawing for this book is found in Vol. 4. 1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Poems and Drawings by Charles Bukowski, Crescent City, Florida, Epos. Presentation to Jon T. Griffith. 1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Longshot Pomes for Broke Players, New York, 7 Poets Press. Presentation to John and Barbara Martin. 1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Run with the Hunted, Chicago, Midwest: A Magazine of Poetry and Opinion, (Midwest Poetry Chapbooks). 1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: It Catches My Heart in Its Hands, New Orleans, Loujon Press (Gypsy Lou Series, 1). Presentation to Jim Roman. Original framed cover for this drawing is found in Vol. 4. 1963 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Crucifix in a Deathhand, New York, Lyle Stuart (Gypsy Lou Series, 2). Presentation to Jim Roman. 1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Cold Dogs in the Courtyard, Chicago, Literary Times-Cyfoeth. Signed on title page. 1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Confessions of a Man Insane Enough to Live With Beasts, Bersenville, Illinois, Mimeo Press. Signed with aphorism. 1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: The Genius of the Crowd, Cleveland, 7 Flower Press. Presentation to Jim Roman. 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: All the Assholes in the World and Mine, Bensenville, Illinois, Open Skull Press. 1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: 2 Poems, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Signed. 1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: The Curtains are Waving and the People Walk Through the Afternoon Here and in Berlin and in New York City and In Mexico, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Signed. 1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: At Terror Street and Agony Way, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. (One of 16 complimentary copies with original misprinted wrapper). Signed. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: At Terror Street and Agony Way, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. (One of 800 copies with Krome Kote label pasted over wrapper misprint.) Signed. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: At Terror Street and Agony Way, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. (Hardbound edition, signed and numbered with an original Charles Bukowski watercolor tipped in.) 1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Poems Written Before Jumping Out of an 8 Story Window, Glendale, California, Poetry X/Change (A Litmus First Edition). Signed on title page. 1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Poems Written Before Jumping Out of an 8 Story Window, Glendale, California, Poetry X/Change. Signed on title page. (One of 25 special copies with original Charles Bukowski watercolor sketch across centerfold.) 1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Poems Written Before Jumping Out of an 8 Story Window. Second edition, Salt Lake City, Litmus, Inc. (Additional material incldues l etters and drawings. Signed on wrapper.) 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Flower, Fist and Bestial Wail. Original ink drawing by Ben Tibbs for the cover. Framed. Pasted to back is a photocopy of Tibbs' letter to Jim Roman explaining drawing. (Volume 4)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Notes of a Dirty Old Man, San Francisco, City Lights Books. (Title first publsihed by Essex House, 1969). 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Aufzeichnungen Eines Aussenseiters, Darmstadt, Joesph Melzer, Verlag. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: A Bukowski Sampler, Madison, Wisconsin, Qixote Press. Signed on wrapper. 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: A Bukowski Sampler, Madison, Wisconsin, Druid Books. Signed on title page. 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: If We Take---, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Signed on title page. 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: If We Take---, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Presentation to Jim Roman. 1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: The Days Run Away Like Wild Horses Over the Hills, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: The Days Run Away Like Wild Horses Over the Hills, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Handbound in boards. Signed with an original pastel drawing tipped in. 1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: The Days Run Away Like Wild Horses Over the Hills, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Galley set. no. 3. Signed. 1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Another Academy Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Fire Station, Santa Barbara, Capricorn Press. Wrapper copy. Signed on cover. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Fire Station, Santa Barbara, Capricorn Press. Hardcover copy. Signed on title page. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Post Office, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Wrapper cover. Signed on cover. 1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Post Office, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Hardcover copy. Signed. 1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Post Office, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Hardbound in boards. Signed with original pastel drawing tipped in. 1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Post Office, London, London Magazines Editions. 1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Der Mann Mit Der Ledertasche, Köln, Verlag Leipenheuer & Witsch. Signed on title page. 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Charles Bukowski's 'Post Office', screenplay by Don Carpenter, Playboy Productions New Visions Inc. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Mockingbird Wish Me Luck, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Wrapper copy. Signed on cover. 1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Mockingbird Wish Me Luck, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Hardcover copy. Signed. 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Mockingbird Wish Me Luck, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Handbound in boards. Signed with original pastel drawing tipped in. 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Mockingbird Wish Me Luck, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Galley set no. 3. Presentation to Jim Roman. 1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: While the Music Played, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press (Sparrow 5). Signed on cover. 1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Sparrow 1-2, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Besides While the Music Played, this contains the following writers: Robert Kelly, Clayton Eshleman, Diane Wakoski, David Bromige, Robert Creely, Richard Grosslinger, David Antin, Sherril Jaffe, Joyce Carol Oates, Michael Palmer, Fielding Dawson.
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Erections, Ejaculations, Exhibitions and General Tales of Ordinary Madness, San Francisco, City Lights Books. Presentation to Jim Roman with drawings. 1972 (Box 7)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Life and Death in the Charity Ward (a different selection and arrangement of stories from Erections... Presentation to Jim Roman. 1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: South of No North, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Wrappers. Signed on cover. 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: South of No North, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Hardcover. Signed. 1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: South of No North, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Handbound in boards. Signed with original watercolor tipped in. 1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: South of No North, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Galley set no. 3. Presentation with drawing to Jim Roman. 1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Gedichte Die Einer Schrieb Bevor Er in 8. Stockwerk Aud Dem Fester Sprang, Gersthofen, Maro Verlag. Both copies signed on title page. 1974 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Burning in Water Drowning in Flame, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Wrappers. Signed on cover. 1974 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Burning in Water Drowning in Flame, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Hardcover signed. 1974 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Burning in Water Drowning in Flame, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Hardcover, library edition. 1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Burning in Water Drowning in Flame, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Handbound in boards. Signed with orginal acrylic tipped in. 1974 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Africa, Paris, Greece, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. Presentation to Jim Roman. 1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Africa, Paris, Greece, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press.Special bound edition. Signed and numbered as part of an original acrylic. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Sparrow 25-36, Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press. 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Besides Africa, Paris, Greece, this contains the following writers: David Bromige, Fielding Dawson, Tom Clark, Theodore Enslin, Michael Watterlond, Diane Wakoski, Nathanial Tarn, Cid Corman, Antonin Artaud, Gerard Malanga, Stephen Stepanchev.
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Factotum, Santa Barbara, Black Sparrow Press. Wrappers. 1975 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Factotum, Santa Barbara, Black Sparrow Press. Hardcover. 1975 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Hardcover. Signed. Factotum, Santa Barbara, Black Sparrow Press. 1975 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Factotum, Santa Barbara, Black Sparrow Press. Handbound in boards. Signed with original acylic tipped in. 1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Factotum, Santa Barbara, Black Sparrow Press. Handbound in boards. Signed. Presentation copy with original acyrlic tipped in. 1975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Factotum, Santa Barbara, Black Sparrow Press. Final proofs. Presentation with drawing to Jim Roman. 1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Scarlet, Santa Barbara, Black Sparrow Press. Hardcover. Signed. 1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Scarlet, Santa Barbara, Black Sparrow Press.Handbound in boards. Signed with original colored drawing on cover. 1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Art, Santa Barbara, Black Sparrow Press. 1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    3A: Wrappers each (2 copies) in mailing envelopes.
    3B: Handbound in boards. Signed.
    3C: Handbound in boards, in slip case. Signed.
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Scarlet, Santa Barbara, Black Sparrow Press. Handbound in silk, completely hand lettered. Signed with an explanatory letter from Black Sparrow Press. 1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Love is a Dog from Hell, Santa Barbara Press. Hardcover. 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Love is a Dog from Hell, Santa Barbara Press. Hardcover. Signed. 1977 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Books and Chapbooks by Bukowski: Love is a Dog from Hell, Santa Barbara Press. Handbound in boards. Signed with an original acrylic tipped in. 1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- IV. Other Publications, 1944-1976
  - Other Publications: Story, v. 24, no. 106. Signed on cover "Aftermath of a Lengthy Rejection Slip." March-April 1944 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Other Publications: Gallows. 1959 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    "What a Man I Was"
    "The Birds"
  - Other Publications: The Outsider, vol. 1, no. 1. Fall 1961 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    "hooray say the roses"
    "pay your rent or get out"
    "shoes"
    "I am with the roots of flowers"
    "go with the rockets & the blondes"
    "a real thing, a good woman"
    "to a high class whore I refused"
    "old man dead in a room"
    "love in a back room on the row"
    "nothing subtle"
    "and then: age"
  - Other Publications: The Outsider, vo9l. 1, no. 2. Contains flyer for The Outsider laid in. Signed on title page. Summer 1962 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    "sick leave"
    "to a lady who believes me dead"
  - Other Publications: Renaissance, vol. 1, no. 3. Signed on cover. 1962 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    "war and piece"